<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-06-28T10:36:00+12:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Laser Kiwi Flag has My Vote</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/post/laser-kiwi-flag/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/post/laser-kiwi-flag/</id>
    <published>2015-06-28T10:36:00+12:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-01T19:28:30+13:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The world's flags are generic as hell. Certain countries have even for a time &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liechtenstein_at_the_1936_Summer_Olympics"&gt;flown the same flag&lt;/a&gt; without realising. Are there really so few 'acceptable flags' that we need to double up? &lt;a href="http://www.quora.com/What-countries-have-very-similar-looking-flags"&gt;A quick look at what the professionals have come up&lt;/a&gt; shows us that our flags are anything but unique representations of our home countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Zealand is in the middle of choosing a new flag. Our current one is derived from British occupation and frankly looks too much like the Australian one. Looking at the proposed replacements, it seems we are keen to trade in looking like the Aussies to looking like some other country. If we exclude the joke designs, the others are the same mash ups of colours seen everywhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what if we didn't exclude the joke ones?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many more joke proposals than serious ones and I think that says something about the character of the country these flags are trying to represent. My favourite is the instantly recognisable Laser Kiwi! There is not a flag in the world which could be confused with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My Photo" title="Laser Kiwi Flag Design: A brown kiwi with a green laser firing out of its eye on a black background" class="img-responsive center-block" src="/content/images/2015-06-27-laser-kiwi/laser-kiwi-flag.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This flag ironically makes me feel more national pride than any serious design ever could. What audacity to fly that flag on the world stage. See already how &lt;a href="https://au.tv.yahoo.com/sunrise/video/watch/28307476/what-about-a-new-flag-eh-bro/"&gt;the Australians laugh at it&lt;/a&gt;. Now imagine that flag flying one place higher than theirs at the next world cup or Olympics. What a time to be alive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A flag should make its citizens feel something. If that something is just a laugh, well what is wrong with that?! We could all benefit a great deal from laughing more. That is surely a far healthier response than remembering old battles and reflecting on the violent history from which the old flag was created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New Zealand thrives on being the underdog. There is no other flag which could so boldly claim that title for ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="disclaimers"&gt;Disclaimers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I am not totally without my wits. It is clearly a joke and will never fly - as sad as that is. The actual design could be taken at least from MS Paint to Photoshop level but I like the spirit of it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Also, both the USA and Great Briton flags do break the generic trend and are pretty nice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If we do have to choose a 'serious flag', this one &lt;a title="Red, white and blue design with a stylised fern running along the diagonal and white stars on blue" href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/nz/news/article.cfm?c_id=1&amp;amp;objectid=11471215"&gt;created by the talented Denise Fung of Christchurch&lt;/a&gt; is looking pretty good too.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Proposed flag" title="Flag designed by Denise Fung" class="img-responsive center-block" src="/content/images/2015-06-27-laser-kiwi/denise-fung-flag.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>RYLA</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/post/ryla/"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/post/ryla/</id>
    <published>2015-05-31T14:54:00+12:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-01T19:28:30+13:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wanted to start off this blog writing about one of the most positive experiences of my life - the Rotary Youth Leadership Award (RYLA). It is an intense six days of personal development for young adults. I was fortunate enough to have been nominated and sponsored by work along with two others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only (minor) downside to sponsorship is that your experience is not entirely your own. Everyone you see at work wants to know about it. I don't hold it against them at all, but what was a deep personal experience gets stripped down to the bare facts through sheer repetition. This post is about how I want to remember it, and what I should take away from it when I think about it years from now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was hard. Very hard.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RYLA was definitely worth the pain but, like a session at the gym, much of the reward comes in retrospect. The most difficult part for me was probably the unrelenting pace of social activities. Being fairly well into the introvert camp, it is important for me to have that processing time. If nothing else, RYLA taught me how much that time really does matter to me. Even if it feels a little silly, take that 10 minutes to go and walk along the river alone. Then come back (this is important!). Come back feeling recharged and ready to dive in once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was glad to leave at the end of the week but one day later, I was ready for round two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="about"&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went along to the &lt;a href="http://www.rotarysouthpacific.org/information.cfm?ID=320"&gt;Rotary District 9930&lt;/a&gt; course. This is the area roughly between Hamilton and Napier in New Zealand. Anyone aged 18 to 28 (or so) in that area who is averse to spoilers may want to leave now with my strongest recommendation that you apply. Even without sponsorship, the cost should not be a deterrent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is run entirely by Rotary volunteers, many of whom are using up annual leave at their day jobs for this. They are a great bunch and really add a lot to the experience. Also kudos to the kitchen crew. Every meal was phenomenal and I have actually been passively losing weight ever since I left. Somehow all the usual snack foods don't taste so good any more and I've been giving them a miss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-1"&gt;DAY 1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time there was a group of 36 youths, bound together by their desire to become leaders and the arbitrary geographic confines of District 9930. We kicked off on a Sunday morning - bright and too early. As people trickled in, we grouped awkwardly around a growing field of imaginary water coolers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn't until we had already stared directly at 35 people's chests that we learned the &lt;strong&gt;name tag goes on the right side&lt;/strong&gt;. It's more visible when shaking hands. (There went that excuse). After a bit of an intro, we were directed to our gender segregated bunks. Choosing one was a pretty hard decision as it would determine how every day started and ended bedtime chatter-wise. I actually changed my mind and then had to awkwardly never talk to those original people ever again. Such is life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was dominated by our colour groups. We were broken into six groups by wearing an outfit of six colours and trading until we had only one complete set. First on my list to trade was my undersized orange suspenders. Somehow that didn't work out and the rest of me turned slowly orange as well. Fortunately they did pop off when I sat down. Unfortunately they almost poked someone in the eye when they did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check us out. I love orange…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My Photo" title="Team Orange" class="img-responsive center-block" src="/content/images/2015-05-31-ryla/team-orange.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did a bit of team building under time pressure, had a session on introducing and thanking guest speakers (TIS: &lt;strong&gt;T&lt;/strong&gt;opic, &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;mportance to audience and &lt;strong&gt;S&lt;/strong&gt;peaker credentials) and finally an intro to rock and roll dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will have to ask someone else how the dancing went - I've repressed those memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-2"&gt;DAY 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two kept up the pace with us splitting in two for some lessons or having fun on the high ropes. Leaping straight out of bed and into a public speaking class might not be for everyone but given the torrential rain outside, we got the best end of that deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The class itself was more philosophical; how you should be memorable and also that if you trust your audience (in a presentation or conversation) then you will share more of yourself and become more engaging. Also if your audience trusts you they will be more likely to give real feedback and therefore engage. Be genuine I think was the message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch there were only gale force winds so we were ready for some climbing! It was pretty fun and my first time doing it. It makes a good trusting exercise on account of needing about four people to safely support each climber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My Photo" title="Taking it easy on the high beam" class="img-responsive center-block" src="/content/images/2015-05-31-ryla/me-on-high-ropes.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't know it yet but I would remain in this pose long after I retuned to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really scary part was yet to come - Masterchef! No I'm not talking about watching C-grade reality TV, this was the real deal. On account of my obvious wish to be somewhere else, I was assigned waiter duties. My job was to serve up our dish to the judges and explain our use of our special ingredient: Black Pudding. Long story short - it's horrible and you should feel bad if you like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My uniform was a mash up of clothes from the others. Being the only male in my group, I was slightly worried I would find my true calling as a drag queen that night. While it was nice feeling fabulous for a while, I'm happy to let that dream stay only a dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-3"&gt;DAY 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3 had us in three rotating groups. Mine started with some reflection in the gym. We were meant to have our Introduction to Pyromania class out at the camp fire but our wet weather alternative was alright as well. We made some nice pictures with coloured paper and a violently terrible symbolic musical performance. The next group was a about running a board meeting. Yeah it was interesting but not a highlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real highlight was the rafting or 'rafting'. The aim was to build a raft and transport all six group members around a marker in the middle of the lake and back. The lake was downstream of a hydro dam which was really cranking up the current. It meant choosing the start point was probably the most important part. You wouldn't  be returning to shore anywhere near it. We had some inner tubes, planks of wood and rope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short - anyone who actually makes a good raft will lose. The ideal shape is probably just six people holding an inner tube while swimming. We weren't quite that cheap (only five swimmers!) but suffice to say the mech/civil engineers I work with were not impressed with the design. That said, we won! Our design was not the optimal one but our team coordination more than made up for it. It was a great way to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My Photo" title="The winning team and we don't even know it yet" class="img-responsive center-block" src="/content/images/2015-05-31-ryla/team-rafting.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-4"&gt;DAY 4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anticipating our encroaching cabin fever, day four was an escape to Hamilton (hold your laughter anyone not from Hamilton). The day was all about interviewing real business and civic leaders. We started off with a talk on communication - words, tone and action. Then into our four person groups to research and write up some practice questions. An hour bus ride later and we arrived in town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our hour together, each leader generally gave advice on the attitudes and behaviours required in their roles. The good news was that they all said different and even contradictory things. We had no context to judge which advice was superior so all we really took away was 'just do your best.' All sorts become leaders and they do it in their own way. I liked that part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think we played spotlight in the evening which was fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-5"&gt;DAY 5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most action packed day and the one where I usually list events from to my colleagues. We were based out on same amazing private farm in Waitomo open only to special groups. This was a chance to apply what we had learned and mainly have some fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, it wouldn't be RYLA if it all went by the book. In that spirit, we were scattered across a field and blindfolded. Each of us had one of four animal names whispered to us. We had to then seek out our group by making the noise of that animal. Five minutes of meowing like crazy later and we were ready to go!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four groups, four activities. First up was the team building exercises. These really focussed on communication and cooperation (what a surprise). We did the famous shuffling along a beam without touching the ground and lowering a long straw to the ground while everyone was touching it; among others. Next up was some rock climbing. This farm really had it all. By this point we had picked up a Jack Russell which was following us everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="My Photo" title="Waitomo team and our escort" class="img-responsive center-block" src="/content/images/2015-05-31-ryla/waitomo-day.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch it was my first attempt at caving. The two dogs clearly had their own territories and we swapped over to a Border Collie escort for the afternoon. The cave was predictably cold and dark inside. It was fun though having the correct gear would have been nice as well. The water level varied between ankle and knee height and we passed cool things like glowworms and fossilised moa bones inside. The dog did follow us quite a way in (despite all attempts to send her away) until the water was finally too deep for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up with the abseiling. Again what farm just conveniently has a sheer cliff in the middle of a field? Everyone was pretty exhausted by this point and even the adventure tour guide with her unlimited energy supply hardly got a word out of us. I only faceplanted once when my shoes slipped but on the whole it was a good, low energy way to wrap up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the bus and we were back at camp around 7pm for another amazing dinner. We also had some preparing to do for our final day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="day-6"&gt;DAY 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By day six I think I was up to about six scoops of coffee in the morning. We were all very drained physically and mentally. Knowing this, we started off low key with more presentations and some of Dale Carnegie's learning exercises. A real unexpected highlight was Brook Turner, CEO of Zeal. He is an amazing speaker and someone who is really making a difference in the world. I can't do him justice here but a few messages were 'What causes anguish is your passion', 'Meet with giants and be inspired by them' and 'Failing is an experience not a state of being'. It was a privilege to hear him talk and to see parts of his then unreleased book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a pretty weird four hour or so gap in the day where we had to leave. Something to do with the rent conditions and check out times. Hopefully by now we had made some friends who we could stick with. I made a beeline straight to the nearest pharmacy for lip balm as I was starting to look ridiculous after being so long without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wrapped it all up with a formal dinner and an evening of presentations and entertainment. I could have happily gone home and slept but it turned out being a good night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="summary"&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RYLA is special. Though I will undoubtedly become sick of talking about it after all the required presentations to sponsors, I just want to remember that it really was a great experience. It was like a school camp but as adults and exclusively with people you liked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is what inspired me to make this blog after years of thinking about it. It made me motivated to take up Spanish lessons again after years of absence. It made me realise I really enjoy public speaking and I want to take it further. RYLA initially feels like a bolt of lightning has hit you and you can do anything. This passes and its a shame but what stays behind is a confidence that you can do the things you care about. They necessarily won't be easy and you won't always succeed. What you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; do is try. No one can take that away from you. You can keep trying again and again as many times as it takes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope one day to be one of those RYLA volunteers and thus complete the circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
